

Peter Koenders | UI/UX & Graphic Designer

- · UI/UX design process
- · Estimating & proposal review
- · Iterative wire-framing & prototypes
- Build & maintain design systems
- · HTML templates & components

I'm a versatile UI/UX designer with over 20 years of all-round industry experience. Originally from a traditional Graphic Design background and transitioned into Digital and Web Design. I support digital accessibility, am curious and enjoy working with creative and integration teams on diversified digital projects.

With professionalism, integrity and care. I work in a collaborative manner to plan, design and deliver crafted solutions.



pkoenders@gmail.com



+64 2115 51085



https://pkoenders.netlify.app



https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-koenders



Westend, Palmerston North, 4410, New Zealand

Work Experience

Contractor - Designer

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

My Life My Voice

Working as a designer/developer for MLMV, I built a multilingual and accessible static website and progressive web app. I used Gatsby as the HTML/JS framework and used Sanity as a headless CMS.

Responsibilities

· Design

Design of web pages, journeys, components ensuring Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1 are adhered to.

Development

Used the Gatsby (JAMStack) framework to build static, progressive web app and multilingual experience (English, Māori + other) for users. Implemented the Sanity API to source content via GraphQL.

Contractor & Volunteer

Jun 2019 - Aug 2020

Sustainable Solutions, Non-profit

I have taken on contract and volunteer work on range of projects as a design professional and front-end developer to keep myself occupied and offering my skills where they can of use.

Design Lead - Contract

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

Vodafone, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Design Lead working with the Content Team, I was accountable for a range of UI design tasks.

Responsibilities

· Digital brand update

Enhance portions of the Vodafone NZ public website and execute a digital brand update.

Design

Re-design web pages, journeys, components. Ensured brand guidelines are adhered to. Deliverables included design files and components, presented for a range of screen sizing and collaborate with stakeholders.

Templates

Created template designs and components to be consistent, work independently and together as a whole.

· Design systems

Designed, built and managed pattern libraries and style guides for design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

Senior Digital Designer

2004 - 2018

Datacom Systems Limited, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Senior Digital Designer in the Digital Experience Team, I grew and developed indispensable skills. I worked with multiple teams and environments. I was accountable for a range of UI/UX, graphic design tasks and had a hand in front-end development.

Responsibilities

· Estimating and proposal review

Defined what efforts would be required for delivery. Review project plans and proposals and made suggestions where value could be added.

Design

Designer for a range of projects, both restrictive and customer facing. Deliverables included design files, templates and prototypes. Iterative wireframes to clarify screen requirements, elements/components and functionality. Explored flows, scenarios and created design options on analysis.

· Design systems

Designed, built and managed pattern libraries and style guides for design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

· HTML prototypes

Created semantic and accessible HTML/SCSS prototypes and templates.

Projects

· Customer facing websites

At Datacom, I initially worked for Air New Zealand managing their CMS; designing and building homepage and landing page takeovers, updating content, integrating new designs and layouts. Other websites, which have since been updated; Bayleys, NZ Lotteries, Ballance, Spark and Fisher & Paykel Finance. Current websites include the HTML/CSS deliverables and translation to responsive design for Auckland Airports and UI/UX design and HTML/CSS deliverables for Aon Insurance.

· Micro-sites and module add-ons

Analysis, flow, wire-frame and design work for Chorus, Spark and Auckland Airports.

Web applications

UI/UX design and HTML deliverables for internal Cloud Services and Payroll applications. External application for Australian Red Cross Blood Service for their Organ Management System used by scientists and medical professionals.

Customer portals

UI design and HTML deliverables for Kotahi Logistics. A customer portal for container ordering, tracking and management.

· Intranets

UI design and HTML deliverables for internal intranet for Datacom. UI Design for Bupa Health. Integration with Microsoft CRM and Salesforce.

· Graphic design

Create and manage print material for internal projects, prepared and composed collateral for internal and external research, analysis and sales presentations.

· Internal innovation hackfests

I participated in annual internal innovation hackfests. Made myself available as a design resource and mentorship of graduates.

Achievements

- I introduced HTML pattern libraries to assist integration teams implementing consistent components.
- · Delivery of accessible and functional HTML templates and prototypes for integration teams and

Web & Print Designer 2001 - 2003

London Centre of Contemporary Music, London, United Kingdom

The LCCM and the London College of Creative Media employed me to design their website. I also worked with their integration team to build their Student Management System. Other tasks I took on; design their identity logo, produce various print materials, course brochures, posters and stationery.

Designer

1996 - 2001

Contract UI Designer, London, United Kingdom

I worked for various design agencies across London in a variety of roles including; UI design for interactive TV, designer hand for Air New Zealand livery and British Telecom, where I was employed to design the UI for a child safe web browser.

Designer 1993 - 1996

Designer, Megabyte/Terabyte, Auckland

Multimedia designer on a range of interactive projects.

Education

Web Accessibility

Deque University

2021 - Present day

Received scholarship to participate in online digital accessibility courses.

Introduction to digital

2020

accessibility

Victoria University

Exploring digital accessibility and what it takes to ensure online content is accessible.

Graded: A-

Diploma of Computer Graphic Design

1992 - 1994

Whanganui School of Design, Whanganui, New Zealand

Three year Diploma of Computer Graphic Design.

Delivery of an interactive design and typography project for final year.

Interests

Outside of my professional interests, supporting my children keeps me busy as a sole parent. I also muck in garden, make chilli jam, listen to vinyl, play the guitar and create DIY tasks.

Cook more vegetarian food and grow more chillies.

